yo Scopus I did promise that I'd be back
tonight I promised so here I am I'm
sitting in the Acura it's me Riccardo
daddy we didn't actually test to see if
the receiving part of the firmware
worked so we might have to wait make
some firmware changes on the flight oh
hey don't worry the scope the scope is
you down to chill welcome to coding with
comma
you should've smashed that like and
subscribe button subscribe though you
don't want to miss Sunday scope e this
weekend big sunday Scobie it's not that
big we're just gonna make we're just
gonna I'm gonna discuss the stream nice
okay so see this wires copies this is
from the comma pedal I scoped it down
there Eddie's out yeah so this is from
the coma pedal down there no we're not
driving when I
there's a tree and you can't really see
it too well got some more lights in here
here's our nice screen get some code
yeah Oconee and chillin you know so we
plug this in here we hope the campus
doesn't short this is the high quality
cable it was a bug in the board minor
bug but we fixed it by cutting water so
if you notice with the , pedal the pedal
still works and this is gonna work 20%
all right oh yeah check it out my foots
off my foots off here you can see my
foot sounds good man so with the common
pedal you can use the joystick actually
I'm not sure he gets to 100% you're
doing good
oh no the car was doing that before it
doesn't okay I was like why is it
revving to 7k it doesn't represent when
you step on it and then I was like oh
maybe the pedal is cutting it out but no
it's not that who's running far as
protection to park yeah what is the
pedal cop the pedal is down here you
can't really see anything
white gonna flash how's the screen
mounted Oh many years ago but yeah yeah
oh yeah look at that you can Rev the
pedal with a joystick that's what the ,
pedal does watch those revs okay so
there's one thing we're redoing pin
oppressor and it's not brushed oh that's
probably just because that changes from
car to car
right like that's a calibration
parameter yeah why are we reading
oh we're reading press you're eating
breasts and then the values like five
six so like your stuff interesting so
what is it normally so you're telling me
this pedal has a slightly different it
learns can you do that remotely yeah
sort of but now we can do it more
directly okay so you're saying that this
is not the zero back no well so it's the
biscuit I'm reading five percent I think
and the car is always reading five
percent yes wait where are you getting
that five from two one no no no but
that's okay that's fine uh what are you
a car gasps reading if you run like
candle right oh I thought you were
telling me that yeah does your position
of a pedal changes over time actually
and it has to learn it right so I think
I need to anything yeah there's just a
number that like zero is five is just
like a fake map thing I think it's
actually always been on my tail so you
can look there in oh did you think that
zero is actually zero well yeah well you
two are well that's kind of the logic
that we were doing before yes so because
in the DBC file like we are playing
offset there was the officer who was
making it zero are you pointing a same
offset so yes there was applied like in
the onboard oh I don't think I'm
applying anything in the board gonna
read the firmware
yeah yes let's go baseball yes check
that one
that's the deck we need to propel the
firm where we may be fine
well I don't really want to like put
things like this on the firmware really
I think this is by design
so you'll you guys will actually see the
firmware already shipped to one
pandaboard pedal not one that's ours but
just hand aboard pedal how does the
pillow look and we still ask o4o how
does the pedal work well so see this is
very sad
- no I just said I just send the value
from the ADC okay I don't do any offset
applying oh yeah it's done in the DBC we
should yeah yeah I don't think when
you're parsing that is that using the
DBC or not it is using the Machine yes
okay so let's see what it says the 0
value is let's just do the math now so
if I look here at the 201 I'm getting
like hex 160
3:52 so you know you guys knees open DBC
same as all y'all
text emojis 550 yeah okay so it's
getting - 83 after I divide by six
clause right and I multiply 89 yeah I
don't know this do destiny first right
yeah that's why would it seeks yeah yeah
but um I mean the petal then has
physically changed on the car that's all
I can say right because otherwise why
else would this happen or the micro
controllers aren't calibrating well and
the different micro controller has a
difference yes but I mean honestly that
should kind of be learned is that saw
the car doesn't it yeah yeah yeah it's
but well how hug you learning how do you
know what zeroes we compare it to car
gas it's actually really easy this is
really yeah because cut well but okay if
it says car gas is zero
yeah it's amazing to respect okay I
guess well I wanna we don't know whether
it's the panel that's changed over time
all of you the new kama petal has a
different value yeah oh you know what
else it could be
the clock race has changed let's just
change it for now yeah that's fine
what do you mean the clock really does
change this panel is also trickier let's
um it's an Allen signal let's wait we
have a hospital reports you can
calibrate it for that for now yeah
that's fine yeah and so okay but so you
still like a problem like if you drift
so I get to do shifting problem no not
over any sort of time yeah this guy said
the car does really can't watch all plus
minus hundred millivolt but yeah so if
you guys see the 201 there and you can
all read this firmware I'm you're gonna
see that it's gonna go up and with a
step on the gas
yeah
changing for this value animal test
across five panels the fight figure out
was the pedal yes thank you
so far now I can just put bike 89 and it
was like yeah I should put like a little
more that's like if you're actually
checking for equals zero well I like to
yeah he needs to be greater than zero
basically yeah write a check for greater
than zero so scope is the reason we're
discussing this is because we want to
detect if the user presses the pedal
because we disengage on a gas press and
when the computers pressing the pedal
the way that we usually detect it using
car gas is still true you have to
distinguish the user from the computer
and now the comma pedal actually looks
like it's uh it just looks like it's the
user yeah well I mean that honestly I
kind of shook it off and EBC in the
first place well I think we should we
should separate it like yeah it should
probably been opened if you see but
shouldn't be in like since now we have
the generator yeah they have a different
file which is like a comma specific
messages and yeah we oughta generate
when you auto generate the file called
Acura ILX we shouldn't put the pedal
interceptor in there right section or we
can we can reload to DBC files what if
we just do that we can like we can
change the faster
you see fights and we merge that in
comparsa that's the love that
where is kama army yeah we don't want to
have to have 201 to every TVC I think
what we should do is just have like
special pedal a nurse like ,
ya guys and this is a note of all the
car manufacturers out there - Oh one's
ours think about it
we use 200 and 201 series we said
say you sent 200 that's what really
power but notice how 201 doesn't change
we do that because that's being applied
after the comma battle if you don't know
what the Kama pedal is check the
previous periscope but I did promise
that you guys would see a working comma
pedal tonight
and I press on this joystick so quick
Parris thank you for joining do I know
who that is no you already you started
using 203 that's fine it's not 201 don't
use 200 all right thank you for joining
in the follow up sculpey we do make
things work we ship we're common a I
make sure to go right now on your
periscope and hit that subscribe button
subscribe got to hit that subscribe
comment pedals never for sale but will
be open-source next week thank you